These are dark time there is no denying.
毫无疑问 黑暗时期已经来临
Our world has prehaps faced no greater threat than it does today.
我们的世界面临着前所未有的威胁
But I say this to our citizens.
但我要对我的人民说
We，ever your servants …
我们 作为你们的公仆
will continue to defend you liberty
会一如既往地捍卫你们的自由
and repel the forces that seek to take it from you.
击退那些企图压迫你们的黑恶力量
Your ministry remains strong.
你们的魔法部依旧强大
（黑魔标记传播着恐怖）
（麻瓜家庭惨遭杀害）
（食死徒数量大增）
Hermione，tea is ready，Darling.
赫敏 亲爱的 茶泡好了
Coming，Mom！
妈妈 来了
Come on！Dudley hurry up.
快点 达力 快
I still don't understand why we have to leave？
我还是不明白 为什么非得走
Because it's not safe around here anymore.
因为这里不再安全了
Ron，tell your father suppers nearly ready.
罗恩 跟爸爸说晚餐快好了
- She's so strong here。- Mm，she's wonderful isn't it.
- 她能应付这些事 - 她多棒啊
Obliviate.
一忘皆空
《哈利波特与死亡圣器（上）》
Severus，I was beginning to worry you had lost your way.
西弗勒斯 我正担心你迷路了呢
Come，we have saved you a seat.
来 给你留了个座位
Do you bring news，I trust.
你应该带来了些情报吧
It will happen Saturday，next。At night fall.
下星期六 夜幕降临之时
I've heard differently my lord.
主人 我听到的有所不同
Dawlish，the auror has let slip that the Potter boy，
那个傲罗德力士无意中透漏
will not be moved until the 30th of this month.
波特要到30号 也就是他满17岁的前一天
The day before he turns 17.
才会转移
This is a false trail.
这是条假情报
The auror office no longer
罗办公室不再参与
plays any part in the protection of Harry Potter.
保护哈利·波特的行动
Those closest to him believe we have infiltrated the Ministry.
凤凰社相信我们的人已经打入了魔法部
Well，they got that right，didn't they.
难得啊 他们总算弄对了一件事
What say you，Pius？
你怎么看 皮尔斯
One hears many things，my lord.
主人 乱花渐欲迷人眼
Whether the truth is among them，is not clear.
哪怕真相就在其中 也很难去伪存真
Spoken like a true politician.
这话说得像个政客
You will I think prove most useful，Pius.
以后会有你发挥的时候 皮尔斯
Where will he be taken，the boy？
他们打算把那男孩藏哪
To a safe house.
一个安全的地方
Most likely the home of someone in the Order.
应该是某个凤凰社成员的家里
I'm told its been given every manner of protection possible.
据说他们已经采取了各种保护措施
Once there it will be impractical to attack him
一旦他到了那里 就很难再抓到他了
My lord，
主人
I'd like to volunteer myself for this task.
我请缨参加这次行动
I want to kill the boy.
我要杀了那男孩
Wormtail！
虫尾巴
Have I not spoken to you about keeping our guest quiet？
我没跟你说过吗 让客人保持安静
Yes，my lord.
是的 主人
Right away，my lord.
马上 主人
As inspiring as I find your bloodlust，Bellatrix.
你这种杀戮的欲望很鼓舞人心 贝拉特里克斯
I must be the one to kill Harry Potter.
但杀死哈利·波特的人 必须是我
But I face an unfortunate complication.
不幸的是 我面临一个难题
That my wand and Potters share the same core.
我和波特的魔杖共用一个杖芯
They are，in some ways，
从某种程度上来说
twins.
它们是双胞胎
We can wound but not fatally harm one another.
虽能造成伤害 但杀不死对方
If I am to kill him，
要想干掉他
I must do it with another's wand.
我必须用另一根魔杖
Come，surely one of you would like the honor.
当然 你们中的一位会享此殊荣
What about you，Lucius？
你怎么样 卢修斯
- My lord？- 「My Lord」？
- 主人 - 「主人」
I require your wand.
我要你的魔杖
- Do I detect elm？- Yes，my Lord.
- 是榆木做的吗 - 是的 主人
And the core？
杖芯呢
- Dragon heartstring，my lord。- Dragon heartstring？
- 龙心腱 主人 - 龙心腱
To those of you who do not know，
也许你们有些人还不知道
we are joined tonight by
今晚我们请到了
Miss Charity Burbage.
凯瑞迪·巴布吉教授
Who until recently taught
她此前
at Hogwarts School of witchcraft and wizardry
一直在霍格沃茨魔法学校教魔法和巫术
Her specialty was muggle studies
她的专长是麻瓜研究
It is Miss Burbage's belief
巴布吉教授相信
that Muggles are not so different from us.
麻瓜与我们毫无差别
She would，given her way，
她认为
have us mate with them.
我们应该与麻瓜通婚
To her the mixture of magical and Muggle blood
用她的话说 麻瓜与巫师通婚
is not an abomination，
不应引以为耻
but something，to be encouraged.
反而值得鼓励
Severus.
西弗勒斯
Severus，please.
西弗勒斯 求你了
We're friends.
我们是朋友
Nagini.
纳吉尼
Dinner.
用餐吧
（讣文：怀念邓布利多）
（作者：埃非亚斯·多吉）
Hello，Harry！
你好 哈利
- Hello！- You're looking fit.
- 你好 - 你看起来不错
Yeah，he's absolutely gorgeous…
那还用说 他绝对没问题
I say lets get undercover，before someone murders him.
我说趁敌人对他动手前 赶快行动
Evening.
晚上好
Kingsley，I thought you were looking after the Prime Minister？
金斯莱 你不是一直在保护麻瓜首相吗
You are more important.
你更重要
Hello Harry。Bill Weasley.
你好 哈利 比尔·韦斯莱
Oh，pleasure to meet you.
很高兴见到你
- He wasn't always so handsome - Daredevil.
- 他平时没这么帅 - 冒失鬼
True enough.
绝对的
Caught one in Wales，
我在威尔士
name of Greyback
捕了一个只灰背
I think I'll favor him one day.
也许有一天我会喜欢上它
Oh you're still beautiful to me，William.
在我眼里你还是那么帅 威廉
Must remember，
你要小心
Fleur Bill takes his steak on the raw side now.
芙蓉·比尔现在迷恋生牛排了
My husband the joker.
我丈夫就爱开玩笑
By the way，wait till you hear the news，
对了 一直想告诉你们
Reamus and I…
我和莱姆斯…
All right then，time for a cozy catch up later.
够了 没时间聊家常了
We've got to get the hell out of here。And soon.
我们必须离开这里 越快越好
Potter，you're underage，
波特 你还未成年
which means you've still got the trace on you.
这意味着你身上仍带有踪丝
What's the trace？
什么踪丝
If you sneezed，
如果你打个喷嚏
the Ministry will know who wipes your nose.
魔法部就会知道谁给你擦的鼻子
The point is we have to use
关键是我们得用
those means of transport the trace can't detect.
踪丝无法探测的方式转移
Brooms，thestrals and the bike。We'll go in pairs.
飞天扫帚 夜骐和飞天摩托 我们结对走
That way if anyone is out there waiting for us，
如果食死徒准备伏击我们
and I reckon there will be，
我觉得他们肯定会来
they won't know which Harry Potter is the real one.
他们分不清哪个才是真正的哈利·波特
The real one？
真正的
I believe you're familiar with this particular brew.
你一定很熟悉这种液体
- No，absolutely not。- I told you he'd take it well.
- 不 绝对不行 - 我说过他会这反应吧
No，if you think I'm gonna let，
不 如果你们认为
everyone risk their lives for me…
我会让每个人为我冒生命危险…
We've done if before，mate.
伙计 咱们之前又不是没干过
No，no，this is different.
不 这次不一样
Taking that，becoming me。No！
喝了它 变成我 不行
Well none of us really fancy it，mate.
其实我们才不喜欢呢 伙计
Yeah，imagine if something went wrong，
想象一下 如果出了什么岔子
and we be stuck as a screwy
我们就永远成为满脸雀斑
specky gits，forever.
疯疯癫癫的小笨蛋了
Everyone here is of age，Potter.
这里的每个人都成年了 波特
They've all agreed to take the risk.
他们愿意冒这个险
Technically，
准确的说
I'd been coerced
我是被胁迫的
Mundungus Fletcher，Mr。Potter.
在下是蒙顿格斯·弗莱彻 波特先生
Always been a huge admirer.
您最忠实的粉丝
Nip it，Mundungus.
闭嘴 蒙顿格斯
Alright Granger，its discussed.
格兰杰小姐 依计而行
Blimey，Hermione！
轻点 赫敏
Straight in here，if you please.
请放进去
For those of you who haven't taken polyjuice potion before，
对于那些没有喝过复方汤剂的人
fair warning.
给你们一个忠告
Tastes like goblin piss.
尝起来有点像妖精的尿
Have enough experiences with that，do you，Mad-eye？
你尝尿无数了是吧 疯眼汉
Just trying to defuse the tension.
活跃一下气氛嘛
Wow！We're identical！
咱俩一摸一样
Not yet you're not.
还没完呢
Haven't you got anything a bit more sporting，have you？
你就没有一件运动型的吗
Yeah，I don't really fancy this color.
我不太喜欢这个颜色
Well fancy this，you're not you，so shove it，and strip.
给你你就穿 由不得你了 快换上
Alright，Alright.
好了 好了
You need to change too，Potter.
你也得换 波特
Bill，look away，I'm hideous.
比尔 头扭过去 我丑死了
I knew she was lying about that tattoo.
我就知道她说的那个纹身是假的
Harry，your eyesight really is awful.
哈利 你的视力真是糟透了
All right then，we'll be pairing off.
好了 我们来分组
Each Potter will have a protector.
每个波特都有一个保护者
Mundungus，stick tight to me.
蒙顿格斯 跟紧我
I want to keep an eye on ya.
我得盯着点你
- As for Harry… - Yes？
- 而哈利… - 这
The real Harry。Where the devil are you anyway？
真正的哈利 到底哪个是你
- Here。- You ride with Hagrid.
- 在这 - 你和海格骑摩托
I brought you here 16 years ago，
我16年前送你来这时
when you were no bigger than a bow truckle.
你还没有一只小史棘龙大
Seems only right that
看起来
I should be the one that take you away now.
解铃还须系铃人啊
Yes，this is all very touching。Let's go！
多感人啊 出发了
Head for the Burrows。We rendezvous there.
目的地陋居 到那碰面
- On the count of three！- Hold tight，Harry！
- 数到三 - 抓紧了 哈利
One！
一
Two！
二
Three！
三
Watch your right！
注意你的右边
Hagrid，we have to help the others！
海格 我们得回去帮他们
Can't do that，Harry.
不行 哈利
Mad-Eye's orders.
疯眼汉有命令
Hang on！
抓紧了
Stupefy！
昏昏倒地
Hang on，Harry！
抓紧了 哈利
Hagrid！
海格
No！No！
不 不
Harry！
哈利
Harry！Hagrid！
哈利 海格
What happened？
发生什么事了
Where are the others？
其他人在哪
Is no one else back？
还没人回来吗
They were on us right from the start，Molly.
我们一出发就被食死徒攻击了 莫丽
We didn't stand a chance.
毫无还手之力
Well，thank goodness you two are all right.
谢天谢地你们俩没事
The Death Eaters were waiting for us。It was an ambush.
食死徒一直在等我们 他们早埋伏好了
Ron and Bill should have already been back.
罗恩和比尔早该回来了
Dad and Fred as well.
爸爸和弗雷德也是
Here.
在这
Quick，into the house.
快 进屋
Oh My boy…
我的孩子
- Come here！- What are you doing？
- 过来 - 你干什么
What creature sat in the corner the
哈利波特在霍格沃兹第一次拜访我的办公室时
first time Harry Potter visited my office in Hogwarts.
房间角落里的是什么生物
- Are you mad？- What creature？
- 你疯了吗 - 什么东西
A Grindylow.
一只格林迪洛
We have been betrayed.
我们被出卖了
Voldemort knew you were being moved tonight.
伏地魔知道我们今晚要转移你
I had to make sure，you weren't an imposter.
我得确定你是不是冒牌货
Wait！
等等
The last words Albus Dumbledore，spoke to the pair of us.
邓不利多最后对我们两个说的什么
「Harry is the best hope we have。」
哈利是我们最大的希望
「Trust him。」
相信他
What gave you away？
你是怎么脱身的
Hedwig，I think.
海德薇来了
She was trying to protect me.
她想保护我
Thanks.
谢谢
He deserves that。Brilliant he was.
你该好好抱抱他 太了不起了
I wouldn't be standing here without him.
要没他我早死了
Really？
真的吗
Why is it so a surprise？
需要这么大惊小怪吗
We the last back？Where's George？
我们是最后一批吗 乔治呢
How are you feeling，Georgie？
乔治 你感觉怎么样
- Saint like。- Come again？
- 像个圣人 - 什么
Saint like.
像个圣人
I'm holey。I'm holey，
我变神圣了 我有洞了
Fred！Get it？
弗雷德 明白吗
A whole wide world of ear related humor
全世界那么多关于耳朵的笑点
and you go for 「I'm holey」.
你偏挑了个「我有洞了」
That's pathetic.
真衰
Think I'm still better looking than you.
我还是比你帅
Mad-Eye's dead.
疯眼汉死了
Mundungus took one look at Voldemort and disapparated.
蒙顿格斯一看见伏地魔就溜了
Head for the burrow.
目的地陋居
Seven，Seven…
七个 七个
- Horcruxes… - They could be hidden anywhere，couldn't they.
- 魂器 - 它们可能藏在任何地方 对吗
To tear the soul into seven pieces…
灵魂裂于七块
If we destroy the Horcruxes.
如果我们摧毁了所有的魂器
One destroys，Voldemort.
就能最终击败伏地魔
Harry…
哈利
- Do not lie to me。Do not lie to me。- No！
- 不要骗我 不要骗我 - 不可以
Going somewhere？
你要去哪
Nobody else is going to die.
再不会有人牺牲了
Not for me.
为我而牺牲
For you？
为了你
You think Mad-Eye died for you？
你以为疯眼汉为你而死
You think George took that curse for you？
你以为乔治为你而伤
You maybe the chosen one，mate…
也许你就是那个救世主
but this is a whole lot bigger than that.
这才是最重要的
Its always been bigger than that.
这比什么都重要
- Come with me。- And leave Hermione？
- 跟我来吧 - 撇下赫敏吗
Are you mad？
你疯了吗
We wouldn't last two days，without her.
没有她咱们撑不了两天
Don't tell her I said that.
别跟她说我说过这话
Besides，you still got the trace on you，
而且 你身上还带着踪丝
you still got the wedding…
你还得参加婚礼
I don't care about a wedding.
我不在乎一个婚礼
I'm sorry，no matter whose it is.
抱歉 不管是谁的婚礼
I have to start finding these Horcruxes.
我必须开始寻找魂器
They're our only chance，to beat him.
那是我们唯一击败他的机会
And the longer we stay here，the stronger he gets.
而我们在这待得越久 他就会越强大
Tonight is not the night，mate.
伙计 今晚还不是时候
You'll only be doing him a favor.
只会正中他的下怀
Do you think he knows？
你觉得他知道吗
I mean they are bits of his soul，these Horcruxes.
那些魂器是他的灵魂碎片
Pieces of him.
是他的一部分
When Dumbledore destroyed the Ring，
当邓布利多毁了那枚戒指
you destroyed Tom Riddle's Diary.
当你摧毁汤姆·里德尔的日记的时候
He must have felt something.
他肯定能感到些什么
To kill the other Horcruxes，we have to find them.
要毁掉剩下的魂器 得先找到它们
Where are they？
它们在哪
Where do we start？
我们从何处着手
（比尔和芙蓉）
（《邓布利多的黑暗面》 丽塔·斯基特新著）
（《追忆邓布利多》 埃非亚斯·多吉著）
Zip me up，will you？
帮我拉上好吗
It seems silly doesn't it，a wedding？
看起来很傻吧 我是说举办婚礼
Given what's going on.
发生了这么多事情
Maybe that's the best reason to have it.
可能这就是举行婚礼最好的理由
Because of everything that's going on.
一切还要继续
Morning.
早啊
All together now！
各就各位
One！Two！Three！
一 二 三
How it looking your end，boys？
你们那边怎么样了 小伙子们
Brilliant.
很好
Bloody，hell。What's the Minister of Magic doing here？
妈的 魔法部长来搞毛
To what do we owe the pleasure，Minister？
部长大人来此有何贵干
I think we both know the answer to that question，Mr。Potter.
这个问题你我都心知肚明 波特先生
This is？
这是什么
Herein it is set forth，
现在我将宣读
the last will and testament of，
阿布思·珀西瓦尔·伍尔弗里克·布赖恩·邓布利多
Albus Percival Wulfric Brian Dumbledore.
最后的遗嘱
「First，to Ronald Billius Weasley，
首先 我要把熄灯器留给
I leave my deluminlator。「
罗恩·比利斯·韦斯莱
「A device，of my own making，
这是我自己做的一个小东西
In the hope，that when things seem most dark…
希望它能在最黑暗的时候
It will show him the light。「
给罗恩带来光明
- Dumbledore left this for me？- Yeah.
- 邓布利多把这个留给我 - 是的
Brilliant.
太棒了
- What is it？- Open it.
- 这怎么使 - 打开它
Wicked.
太帅了
「To Hermione Jean Granger，
将我珍藏的《诗翁彼豆故事集》
I leave my copy of 'The Tales of Beedle the Bard'.「
留给赫敏·简·格兰杰
「In the hope that she find it entertaining and instructive 」
希望她能从书中找到乐趣和启发
My mom used to read me those.
我妈以前常给我读
The wizard and the hopping pot，
精灵和魔力壶
Babbity Rabbity and the Cackling Stump.
芭比兔与话唠树桩
Come on。Babbity Rabbity.
得了 芭比兔啊
No？
没听过吗
「To Harry James Potter
哈利·詹姆斯·波特
I leave the snitch he caught
将得到这只金色飞贼
「in his first
这是他在霍格沃茨
Quidditch match at Hogwarts.
第一次参加魁地奇比赛时抓到的
As a reminder of the rewards of perseverance…
以时刻提醒他
and skill.「
毅力和技巧的回报
Is that it then？
就这些吗
Not quite.
还没
Dumbledore left you，
邓布利多还留给你
a second bequest.
第二件遗物
The sword of Godric Gryffindor.
戈德里克·格兰芬多之剑
Unfortunately，the sword of Gryffindor
很不幸 邓布利多没有权利
was not Dumbledore's to give away.
将格兰芬多之剑赠予他人
As an important historical artifact it belongs…
作为一件贵重的历史文物 它属于…
to Harry.
哈利
It belongs to Harry.
它属于哈利
It came to him when he most needed it
在密室里 当哈利最需要的时刻
in the Chamber of Secrets.
它选择了哈利
The sword may present itself
每当遇到格莱芬多的杰出学生时
to any worthy Gryffindor，Miss Granger，
宝剑就会出现 格兰杰小姐
that does not make it that wizards property.
这并不表示它属于那个人
And in any event，
更何况
the current whereabouts of the sword are unknown.
现在没人知道宝剑在哪
Excuse me？
你说什么
The Sword is Missing.
剑不见了
I don't know what you are up，to，Mr。Potter，
我不知道你接下来要做什么 波特先生
but you can't fight this war on your own.
但你不能单打独斗
He's too strong.
他太强大了
Hello，Harry.
你好 哈利
I've interrupted your deep thoughts，haven't I？
我打扰了你的沉思吗
I see it growing small in your eyes.
我从你的眼睛里看得出来的
Of course not。How are you，Luna？
当然没有 你好吗 卢娜
Very well，
很好
I've been bitten by garden a gnome and numbed my thumb.
我被地精咬了一口 大拇指失去知觉了
Gnome saliva is very beneficial.
地精唾液可大有裨益哦
Xenophilius Lovegood.
谢诺菲留斯·洛夫古德
We live just over the heel.
我们住在山上
Nice to meet you，sir.
很高兴见到你 先生
I trust you know Mr。Potter that we at the Quibbler，
相信波特先生知道我们的《唱唱反调》
disagree with the Daily Prophet，
跟《预言家日报》对着干
and have always fully supported Dumbledore…
我们在邓布利多在世时和他去世后
during his lifetime and in his death，support you just as fully.
都全力支持他 也全力支持你
Thank you.
谢谢
Come Daddy。Harry doesn't want to talk to us right now.
好了爸爸 哈利现在不想跟我们说话
He's just too polite to say so.
他只是怕有失礼貌
Excuse me，sir.
抱歉 先生
- May I sit down？- Mr。Potter.
- 我能坐吗 - 波特先生
By all means，here.
请便
I found what you wrote in the Daily Prophet，
我看了你在预言家日报上写的文章
really moving.
非常感人
You obviously knew Dumbledore well.
你一定 很了解邓布利多吧
Well，I certainly knew him the longest.
我认识他的时间最长了
Unless we don't count his brother Aberforth，
除了他弟弟阿不福思外
and somehow people never do seem to count，Aberforth.
不过 好像从没人记起过阿不福思
I didn't even know he had a brother.
我都不知道他还有个弟弟
Dumbledore was always very private，even as a boy.
邓布利多一直独来独往 从小就是
Do not despair，Elphias.
别惆怅了 埃菲亚斯
I'm told he's been thoroughly unrevealed by Rita Skeeter.
丽塔·斯基特曝光了他的一切
In 800 pages.
书有800页厚呢
Word has it
据说
that someone talked to her.
有人向她透露了些秘密
Someone who knew the Dumbledore family well.
一个与邓布利多家族关系密切的人
Both you and I know who that is，Elphias.
咱俩都知道这指的是谁吧 埃菲亚斯
A monstrous betrayal.
这是可耻的背叛
Who are，who are we talking about？
这个 这个人是谁啊
Bathilda Bagshot.
巴希尔达·巴肖特
Who？
谁
My god，boy。She is only the most…
天哪 孩子 她可是
celebrated magical historian of the last century.
上个世纪最著名的魔法史家
She was as close to the Dumbledore's as anyone.
还是邓布利多的老朋友
Oh，I'm sure Rita Skeeter
丽塔·斯基特肯定觉得
thought it well worth a trip to Godric's Hollow，
很值得去一趟戈德里克山谷
to take a peek into that old bird's records cage.
拜访一下那个老不啦叽的女人
Godric's Hollow？
戈德里克山谷
Bathilda Bagshot lives in Godric's Hallow？
巴希尔达·巴肖特住在戈德里克山谷吗
That's where she first met，Dumbledore.
她就是在那认识邓布利多的
You don't mean to say he lived there too.
你不会是说邓布利多也住在那吧
The family moved there
他爸爸杀了那三个麻瓜后
after his father killed those three Muggles.
全家就搬了过去
It was quite the scandal.
那可是当时很大的丑闻
Honestly my boy，
孩子 说真的
are you sure you knew him at all？
你真的了解邓布利多吗
Ministry has fallen.
魔法部垮台了
Minister of Magic，is dead.
魔法部长死了
They are coming.
他们来了
Nice meeting you，Mr。Potter.
后会有期了 波特先生
Ginny！
金妮
Go！Go！
快走 快走
Where are we？
我们这是在哪
Shaftesbury Avenue.
舍夫茨别利路
I used to come up here to theaters with mom and dad.
我以前常和爸妈来这看戏
I don't know why I thought of it。It just popped into my head.
我也不知道怎么想到的 它突然就蹦了出来
This way.
这边
We need to change.
我们得换身衣服
Bloody Hell
活见鬼了
- Undetectable Extension charm。- You're amazing，you are.
- 空间扩增咒 - 你真厉害
Always a total surprise.
生活充满着惊喜
Ah，that'll be the books.
剩下的就是那堆书了
What about all the people at the wedding？
婚礼上的人怎么办
Do you think that we should go back？
我们是不是该回去看看
They're after you，mate.
伙计 他们冲你来的
We'd put everyone in danger by going back.
回去的话 大家都会有危险
- Ron's right。- Coffee
- 罗恩说的对 - 要什么咖啡
- A cappuccino please - You？
- 一杯卡布奇诺 - 你呢
- What she said。- Same.
- 和她一样 - 一样
So where do we go from here？Leaky Cauldron.
那我们现在去哪 破釜酒吧
It's too dangerous.
太危险了
If Voldemort has taken over the Ministry，
如果伏地魔控制了魔法部
none of the old places are safe.
就没哪是安全的了
Everyone from the wedding would have gone underground，into hiding.
婚礼上的人也都该躲起来了
My rucksack with all my things。I've left it at the burrow.
我的包还在陋居 东西都在里面
You're joking.
你开玩笑吧
I had the essentials，packed for days。Just in case.
我几天前就把必需品装包里了 以防万一
By the way，why're the jeans not my favourite？
对了 我最喜欢的牛仔裤怎么没带上
Down！
趴下
Stupify！
昏昏倒地
Petrificus Totalus！
统统石化
Go！Leave.
快走 离开这
Lock the door，get the lights.
锁上门 熄掉灯
This one's names Rawl.
这个是罗尔
He was on the astronomy tower the last night they killed Dumbledore.
邓布利多被杀的那晚 他也在占星塔上
This is Dolohov.
这个是多罗霍夫
I recognize him from the wanted notice.
我在通缉布告上见过
So what we're gonna do with you，eh？
怎么处置你们呢
Kill us if it was turned round，wouldn't you？
反过来 你们会杀了我们对吧
We kill them，they'll know we were here.
杀了他们的话 食死徒就知道我们在哪了
- Ron。- Suppose he did Mad-eye？How would you feel then？
- 罗恩 - 没准是他杀的疯眼汉呢 你还那么想吗
It's better we wipe their memories.
抹去他们的记忆吧
You're the boss。Hermione.
你说了算 赫敏
You're the best with spells.
魔咒什么的你最拿手
Obliviate.
一忘皆空
How is it they knew we were there？
他们怎么找到我们的
Maybe you still have the trace on you？
你可能还带着踪丝
They can't，the trace stays until I'm seventeen year's old.
不可能 十七岁踪丝就消失了
What？
怎么了
We didn't celebrate your birthday，Harry.
我们还没给你过生日呢 哈利
Ginny and I，we prepared a cake.
我和金妮还准备了个蛋糕
We were going to bring it out at the end of the wedding.
我们准备在婚礼结束时拿出来
Hermione，honestly，
赫敏 说真的
I appreciate the thought，
你的好意我心领了
but really given the fact，that we were almost killed
但是看看刚才 我们差点被几个食死徒杀了
by a couple of Death Eaters a few minutes ago.
还是先别想这个了吧
Right… perspective.
也是 说的对
We have to get off the streets，get to someplace safe.
咱们别在街上晃悠了 找个安全的地方
What was that all about？
刚才那是什么
Probably Mad-Eye's idea.
应该是疯眼汉的主意吧
In case Snape decides to come snooping.
防止斯内普偷摸进来
Homenum Revelio.
人形显身
We're alone.
没有别人了
Another wand！
换一根魔杖
I believe a different wand would work？I swear.
我发誓 再换一根就行了
It should be another way.
应该有别的方法
Harry，where are you？
哈利 你在哪
Is it dark up there？
上面黑吗
Lovely.
还不错嘛
Regulus Arcturus Black
雷古勒斯·阿克图勒斯·布莱克
R.A.B.
R.A.B…
「I know I will be dead long before you read this。」
在你读到这个之时 我早已死去
「I have stolen the real horcrux and intend to destroy it。」
我偷走了真的魂器 并想销毁它
R.A.B，he was Sirius' brother？
R.A.B 是小天狼星的弟弟吗
Yes.
对
The question is he didn't actually destroy the real Horcrux.
但问题是他没能摧毁真正的魂器
Spying on us，have you.
你一直暗中监视我们
Kreacher，has been watching.
克利切 一直在旁观
Maybe he knows where the real locket is？
也许他知道真的魂器在哪
Have you ever seen this before？Kreacher？
你以前见过这个东西吗 克利切
- It is Master Regulus's locket！- There were two，weren't there？
- 是雷古勒斯少爷的挂坠盒 - 当时有两个 对不对
Where's the other one？
另一个呢
Kreacher doesn't know，about the other locket.
克利切不知道另一个挂坠盒在哪
Yes，but did you ever see it？It was in this house.
但你以前见过吗 它就在这所房子里
Filthy mudblood that's what you are，Blood traitor Weasley！
肮脏的泥巴种 还有血统背叛者韦斯莱
Answer her.
回答她的问题
Yes.
见过
It was here，
它曾经就在这里
in this house.
在这屋中
Most evil object.
这邪恶的物件
How do you mean？
什么意思
Before Master Regulus died，he ordered Kreacher to destroy，
雷古勒斯少爷死前 命令克利切销毁它
but no matter how hard Kreacher tried，he could not do it.
但试遍了所有的办法都不行
Well，where is it now？
现在在哪
- Did someone take it？- He came in the night.
- 有人拿走了吗 - 他那天晚上来到这
He took many things including the locket.
连带着挂坠盒拿走了很多东西
Who did？Who was it，Kreacher？
谁 谁拿走的 克利切
Mundungus.
蒙顿格斯
Mundungus Fletcher.
蒙顿格斯·弗莱奇
Find him.
找到他
My father will hear about this.
我爸饶不了你们
Hey losers。He isn't here.
饭桶们 他不在这
（哈利波特：头号不良分子）
As your new Minister for Magic，
作为你们的新任魔法部长
I promise to restore this temple of tolerance
我承诺将给这恢弘的大厅
to its former glory.
带回往昔的荣耀
（魔法即强权）
Therefore beginning today，
因此从今天开始
each employee will submit themselves，
每位职员都必须接受
for evaluation.
血统评估
But know this，you have nothing to fear，
记住 如果你没什么可隐瞒的
if you have nothing to hide.
就应无所畏惧
They have flesh memories.
金色飞贼有肉体记忆
When Scrimgeour first gave it to you，
斯克林杰给你的时候
I thought，it might open at to your touch.
我还想 它一碰到你的手就会打开
That Dumbledore hidden something inside it.
邓布利多可能在里面藏了什么东西
Harry Potter，how long it's been！
哈利·波特 好久不见了啊
Get off me！
滚开
Expelliarmus！
除你武器
What you playing at？
你们玩得什么把戏
Setting a pair of bleeding house elves after me？
派一对家养小精灵跟踪我吗
Dobby was only trying to help.
多比只是想帮忙
When Dobby saw Kreacher in Diagon Alley，
多比在对角巷看到克利切的时候
Which Dobby thought was curious.
多比很好奇他怎么会来这里
And then Dobby heard Kreacher mention Harry Potter's name.
然后多比就听到他提到哈利·波特
And then Dobby saw Kreacher talking with the thief.
之后多比看到克利切和那个贼说话
Not a thief？You foul little…
你才是贼 你这小…
git.
杂种
I'm a purveyor of rare and wondrous objects.
我只是转手一些珍贵奇妙的玩意
You're a thief，Dung，everyone knows it.
你就是个贼 顿格 大家都知道
- Master Weasley，so good to see you。- Like your shoes.
- 韦斯莱少爷 见到你真高兴 - 鞋子不错
Listen，I panicked that night，alright？
听着 我那天晚上紧张极了
Can't help it if Mad-Eye fell off his broom.
疯眼汉跌落扫帚 我有什么办法
- You。- Tell the truth.
- 你 - 说实话
When you turned this place over，
你把这翻个底朝天的时候
don't deny it，
别说没有
you found a locket，am I right？
找到了个挂坠盒 对吗
Why，was it valuable？
怎么了 很值钱吗
- So，was it？- He's worried he didn't get enough money for it.
- 是吗 - 他担心卖的钱太少了吧
Bleeding give it away，didn't I？
我可是忍痛割爱了
There I was plogging my wares in Diagon alley，
那天我在对角巷兜售货物
when some Ministry hag comes up and asks to see me license.
突然有个魔法部的女巫过来要看我的许可证
Says she the one would lock me up.
说没有的话就把我关起来
Would have done too，if she hadn't taken a fancy to that locket.
要不是她突然看上那个挂坠盒 我就真被关起来了
Who was it？The witch，do you know her？
是谁 你认识她吗
Know her？
认识
She's there。Look.
就是她 瞧
Bleedin' bone who.
绝对没错
（魔法部寻求教育改革）
Right，remember what we said.
好了 记住我们之前说好的
Don't speak to anyone，unless absolutely necessary.
除非迫不得已 不要跟任何人说话
Just，try and act normal.
尽量表现得正常点
Do what everybody else is doing.
依葫芦画瓢
If we do that and with a bit of luck we'll get inside.
这样运气好的话 我们就能进去了
- And then… - It gets really tricky.
- 然后 - 随机应变了
Correct.
没错
- This is completely mental。- Completely.
- 这真是疯了 - 没错
The world's mental。Come on.
世界本疯癫 喝吧
We have a Horcrux to find.
我们要去找魂器
（男厕所）
We flush ourselves in.
得把自己冲进去
Its bloody disgusting.
恶心死了
- You，come along。- What，what？
- 你 过来 - 怎么了
What did I do？
我怎什么了
- Are those… - Muggles.
- 那些是 - 麻瓜
In their… rightful place.
在他们该待的地方
Got to tell you，I'm starting to freak out a bit.
说实话 我有点崩溃了
How long did you say this batch of polyjuice will last，Hermione？
你说这个复方汤剂药效有多久来着 赫敏
I didn't.
不知道
Cattermole.
卡特莫尔
Its still raining inside my office。Its two days now.
我办公室还在下雨呢 两天了
Have you tried an umbrella？
试过撑把伞吗
Do you realize I'm going downstairs don't you，Cattermole？
你知道我正要去楼下吧 卡特莫尔
- Downstairs？- To interrogate your wife.
- 楼下 - 审问你妻子
Now if my wife's blood status were in doubt，
如果有人怀疑我妻子的血统
and the Head of Department
同时魔法部
of Magical Law Enforcement needed a job doing，
法律执行司的头有个活要做
I think I might just make that a priority.
我一定会把它当做头等大事去办
You have one hour.
给你一个小时
Oh my god，what am I gonna do？
天啊 我该怎么办
My wife's all alone downstairs.
我妻子一人在楼下
Ron，you don't have a wife.
罗恩 你哪来的妻子
Oh right.
也对
Level Two.
第二层
But how do I stop it raining？
但怎么让雨停下来呢
Try 「Finite Incantatem」.
试试咒立停
This is you，Ron.
你到了 罗恩
Finite Incantatem，okay.
咒立停 好的
And if that doesn't work？
没效果怎么办
I say if we don't locate Umbridge within the hour，
如果一小时内没找到乌姆里奇
we go find Ron and come back another day.
那我们就跟罗恩回去 改天再来
- Deal？- Yes.
- 行吗 - 好
Ah，Mafalda。Trevor sent you，did he？
马法尔达 特雷弗派你过来的是吧
Good。We'll go straight down.
很好 我们下楼去
Albert，weren't you getting out？
艾伯特 你不出去吗
（危险的泥巴种）
Runcorn？
伦考恩
（多洛雷斯·乌姆里奇 魔法部高级副部长）
（麻瓜出身登记委员会主任）
Accio locket！
挂坠盒飞来
All right，all right。Let's calm down.
好了好了 冷静下来
Lets get back to work，please.
继续工作好吗
Calm down.
没事了
Runcorn？
伦考恩
Morning.
早
- Ron，it's me。- Harry！
- 罗恩 是我 - 哈利
Blimey！Forgot what you look like.
天啊 我都忘你什么样了
Where's Hermione？
赫敏呢
She's gone down to the court rooms，with Umbridge.
她跟乌姆里奇到楼下法庭去了
Bloody cold down here.
这里冷死了
I'm half blood。My father，my father was a wizard.
我是混血 我爸 我爸是巫师
William Waldenten，he worked here for 30 years.
威廉·沃登顿 在这工作30年了
Perhaps you know him。He Always wore a jacket inside out.
你们没准记得 老是反穿夹克的那个
There must be a mistake.
一定是弄错了
Tell the ministry，I must go to work，I'm half blood.
跟魔法部说 我必须回去工作 我是混血
Mary Elizabeth Cattermole，
玛丽·伊丽莎白·卡特莫尔
of 27 Chislehurst Gardens，Great Tolling，Itchum.
奇斯尔赫斯特花园27号
- Yes。- It's here.
- 对 - 就是这
Mother to Maisie，Ellie and Alfred; Wife to Reginald？
梅齐 埃利和阿尔弗雷德的母亲 雷吉纳德的妻子
Regi.
雷吉
Thank you，Albert.
谢谢你 艾伯特
Mary Elizabeth Cattermole.
玛丽·伊丽莎白·卡特莫尔
Yes？
怎么了
A wand was taken from you upon
卡特莫尔太太 你今天抵达魔法部时
your arrival at the Ministry today，Mrs。Cattermole
被收走了一根魔杖
Is this that wand？
是这根吗
Would you please tell the court，
能否告诉我们
from which witch or wizard you took this wand？
你是从谁那里抢来的
I didn't take it.
我没有抢
I bought it at Diagon Alley，at Ollivanders，when I was 11.
我十一岁的时候在对角巷奥利凡德那买的
It chose me.
它选择了我
You're lying.
你在撒谎
Wands only choose witches，and you are not a witch.
魔杖只选择巫师 而你不是巫师
But I am.
我是
Tell them，Reg，tell them what I am.
雷吉 告诉他们我是谁
Reg，tell them who I am.
告诉他们我是巫师
What on earth are you doing，Albert？
你究竟想干嘛 艾伯特
You're lying，Dolores.
你在撒谎 多洛雷斯
And one mustn't tell lies.
你不可以撒谎
Stupefy！
昏昏倒地
Oh，it's Harry Potter！
天哪 是哈利·波特
It's him isn't it。This is one to tell the kids.
就是他 这下跟孩子们可有故事讲了
Expecto patronum！
呼神护卫
Mary，go home.
玛丽 回家吧
Get the kids.
带上孩子
I'll meet you there.
我去那找你
We have to get out of the country，understand？
国内待不下去了 明白吗
Mary，do as I say.
玛丽 照我说的做
Mary？
玛丽
Who's that？
那是谁
Long story，nice meeting you.
说来话长 见到你真高兴
- Harry Potter。- It's Harry，Harry Potter.
- 哈利·波特 - 是哈利 哈利·波特
Expelliarmus！
除你武器
Harry，Harry，quickly，in my bag.
哈利 哈利 快点 在我包里
There's a bottle labeled 「Essence of Dittany」.
有个瓶子上写着白鲜香精
Quickly！
快点
Accio Dittany！
香精飞来
All right，unstopper it.
打开瓶子
Hermione，his arm.
赫敏 他的胳膊
I know，just do it！
我知道 快打开
It's gonna… It's gonna sting a little bit.
可能 可能会有点痛
What happened？
怎么了 我以为
I thought we were going to go back to Grimmauld Place.
咱们不是要回格里莫广场的吗
We were。Alright，One more，one more.
确实是 再来一点 再来一点
We were there we were there but，Yaxley had a hold of me，
我们到了 但是亚克斯利抓住了我
I knew once he'd seen where we were we，
他一旦知道了咱们去哪
we couldn't stay so，
那地方就没法待了
I brought us here，but，
所以我就把你们带到这来了
Ron got splinched.
罗恩被分体了
Protego Totalum.
统统加护
- Salvio Hexia。- What are you doing？
- 平安镇守 - 你在干吗
Protective enchantments.
守护魔咒
I don't fancy another visit
我可不想再像舍夫茨别利路那
like the one we had at Shaftesbury Avenue，do you？
碰上几个不速之客了
You can get going on a tent.
你可以把帐篷拿出来
Tent？
帐篷
- Protego Totalum。- Where am I supposed to find a tent？
- 统统加护 - 帐篷在哪
Repello Muggletum。Muffliato.
麻瓜屏蔽 闭耳塞听
You first.
你先来
Incendio.
火焰熊熊
Expulso！
飞沙走石
Diffindo！
四分五裂
Reducto！
粉身碎骨
What are you doing？
你干嘛
We have to keep it safe，until we find out how to destroy it.
在找到毁掉它的方法前 我们得保管好它
Seems strange，mate.
有点奇怪啊 哥们
Dumbledore sent you off to find these Horcruxes，
邓布利多让你去找魂器
but doesn't tell you how to destroy them.
但却没告诉你怎么毁掉它们
Doesn't that bother you？
你不觉得奇怪吗
You know the spell，Harry.
你知道那个咒语 哈利
- Tell me，Gregorovitch。- He stole from me.
- 告诉我 格里戈维奇 - 他从我这偷走的
Who was he，the thief？
那小偷是谁
The boy。It was he who took it.
一个男孩 被他拿走了
I never saw it again，I swear on my life.
我再也没见过他 我以生命起誓
I believe you.
我相信你
Avada Kedavra！
阿瓦达索命
I thought it stopped.
梦做完了吧
You can't keep letting him in，Harry.
你不能一直让他这样侵入你的大脑
- You-Know-Who has found，Gregorovitch。- The Wand Maker？
- 神秘人找到了格里戈维奇 - 那个魔杖匠人
He wants something that Gregorovitch used to have.
他想要一个格里戈维奇以前拥有的东西
I don't know what。But he wants it desperately.
不知道是什么 但是他迫切地想拿到手
I mean，it's as if his life depends on it.
仿佛那东西承载着他的性命
Don't，it comforts him.
别 有助他恢复
It sets my teeth on edge.
让我浑身发毛
What's he expecting to hear，good news？
他想听到什么好消息吗
I think he just hopes that he doesn't hear bad news.
他应该只是不想听到坏消息
How long before he can travel？
他还有多久才能移形
- I… I'm doing everything I can。- You're not doing enough.
- 我 我尽力了 - 还不够
Take it off！
拿下来
I said，Take it off，now！
我说了 马上拿下来
- Better？- Right.
- 好点了吗 - 嗯
We'll take it in turns，okay？
我们轮流戴吧
Severus Snape voted in as headmaster of Hogwarts.
西弗勒斯·斯内普被选为霍格沃茨魔法学校校长
（校长办公室）
（西弗勒斯·斯内普）
What's that？
等等
What's that，smell？
这什么味道
Whatcha doing？It's heavy.
你在干嘛 东西沉死了
Oh I'm sorry。Do you want me to carry it？
不好意思 要我帮忙拿吗
Snatchers.
掠夺贼
Good to know your enchantments work.
多亏了你的魔法
He could smell it，my perfume.
他闻到了我的香水
I told you，
我告诉过你
Ron isn't strong enough to apparate.
罗恩还无法驾驭幻影移形
Well then，we'll go on foot.
那我们就走去吧
Only next time，as much as you like your perfume，
下次不管你多想喷香水
just don't wear any.
都克制点别用
And now for the names of missing witches and wizards.
现在播报失踪巫师名单
These are confirmed，
这些是已确认名单
thankfully the list is short today.
所幸的是 今天的名单很短
Jason and Alison Denbright.
杰森 艾莉森·邓布莱特
Oh，thank you.
谢谢
Bella，Jake，Charlie，and Madge Farley.
贝拉 詹克 查里 麦基·法利
Joe Laurie.
乔·拉瑞
Eleanor Sarah Gibbs.
埃莉诺·莎拉·吉布斯
Harry and Bronwyn Trigg.
哈利 布朗温·崔格
Rob and Ellie Dowson.
罗勃 艾利·道森
Georgia Clark-Day.
乔治亚·德·克莱克
Joshua Flexson.
约书亚·佛莱克斯
George Coutas.
乔治·库塔斯
Gabriella and Emily Mather.
加布里埃拉 艾米丽·马瑟
Jacob and Mimi Erland.
雅各布 米·厄兰
William and Brian Gallagher.
威廉和布莱恩·加拉格尔
He doesn't know what he's doing，does he？
他不知道自己在做什么 是吗
None of us do.
我们都不清楚
Katie and James Killick.
凯蒂 詹姆斯·克里克
Elsie Valentine Schroeder.
埃尔希·瓦伦丁·施罗德
Jennifer Winston.
珍妮弗·温斯顿
Tamsin and Iola Hillicker.
塔姆辛 约拉·希里克
- Oh My God！- What？
- 我的天啊 - 怎么了
I'll tell you in a minute.
马上告诉你
Maybe you can tell me now.
现在不行吗
Sword of Gryffindor。It's goblin made.
格兰芬多剑 是妖精做的
Brilliant.
真聪明
No，you don't understand.
不 你没听懂
Dirt and rust have no effect on the blade.
泥土和铁锈不会沾染剑锋
It only takes in that which makes it stronger.
它只会吸收能增强自己力量的东西
O… kay.
所以呢
Harry，we've already destroyed one horcrux，right？
哈利 我们不是已经摧毁了一个魂器吗
Tom Riddle's diary in the Chamber of Secrets.
汤姆·里德尔密室里的日记
With a basilisk fang.
用的是蛇怪的毒牙
If you tell me you've got one of those
别告诉我你那血迹斑斑的珠绣包里
in that bloody beaded bag of yours…
也有根毒牙
Don't you see？
你还不明白吗
In The Chamber of Secrets，
在密室里
you stabbed the Basilisk with the sword of Gryffindor.
你用格兰芬多剑杀死了蛇怪
Its blade is impregnated with basilisk venom.
它的刀刃沾染了蛇怪的毒液
It only takes in that which makes it stronger.
它只会吸收增强自己力量的东西
- Exactly，which is why… - It can destroy Horcruxes.
- 对 这就是为什么 - 它能摧毁魂器
That's why Dumbledore left it to you in his will.
这就是邓不利多遗嘱的本意
You're brilliant，Hermione。Truly.
你太聪明了 赫敏 真的
Actually，I'm highly logical
其实是因为我的逻辑
which allows me to slip past extraneous details.
能让我把无关细节联系起来
And perceive clearly that which others overlook.
而且能观察到别人忽略的东西
Yeah，there is only one problem with this.
是的 但有个问题
The sword was stolen.
剑被偷了
Yeah，I'm still here.
瞧 我还在这
But you two carry on.
你们俩继续
Don't let me spoil the fun.
别因为我扫了兴
- What's wrong？- Wrong？Nothing's wrong.
- 怎么了 - 没怎么啊
According to you，anyway.
你想怎样就怎样
If you got something to say，don't be shy.
如果你想说什么 别藏着掖着
Spit it out.
说出来
Alright，I'll spit it out.
那我可就说了
But don't expect me to be grateful
别以为咱们现在要去找另一个鬼玩意了
just because now it's another damn thing we got to find.
我就能开心点
I thought you knew what you signed up for.
我以为你知道此行的目的
Yeah，I thought it too.
我也这么想来着
I'm sorry。But I don't quite understand.
不好意思 我有点不明白
What part of this isn't living up to your expectations？
到底哪一点让你不满意了
Did you think we were going to be staying in a five star hotel？
你是不是认为我们该住五星级酒店
Finding a Horcrux every other day.
三天打渔两天晒网
You thought you'd be back with your mum by Christmas？
你还盼着回家和老妈过圣诞节是吗
I just thought，after all this time
我只是觉得 都这么久了
we would actually have achieved something.
我们应该有点进展
I thought you knew what you were doing.
我以为你知道该怎么做
I thought Dumbledore would have told you something worthwhile.
邓不利多应该告诉过你一些有价值的信息
I thought you had a plan.
我以为你有计划
I told you everything Dumbledore told me.
邓不利多和我说的我都告诉你了
And in case you haven't notice we have found a Horcrux already.
而且我们已经找到了一块魂器
And we're as close to getting rid of it
找到了一个
as we are to finding the rest of them，aren't we？
就万事大吉了吗
Ron，Please，take off the Horcrux.
罗恩 把魂器取下来
You wouldn't be saying any of this
如果你没整天戴着这个
if you hadn't been wearing it all day.
就不会这么说
You don't know，why I listen to the radio every night，do you？
知道我为什么每晚都要听广播吗
To make sure I don't hear Ginny's name，
我想确认名单上没有金妮
or Fred，or George or Moms.
弗雷德 乔治 还有我妈
You think I'm not listening too？
你以为我没听吗
You think I don't know how it feels？
你以为我不知道这什么感觉吗
No you don't know how it feels！
你就是不知道
Your parents are dead！You have no family！
你父母死了 你没有家人
Stop！Stop！
别打了 停下
- Let me go！- Go then！
- 让我走 - 你走啊
Ron！
罗恩
And you？
你呢
Are you coming or are you staying？
跟我走还是留下
Fine，I get it。I saw you two the other night.
我明白了 我那晚看见你们了
Ron there's… there's nothing.
罗恩 我和他之间没什么
Ron！
罗恩
Ron，where are you going？
罗恩 你去哪
Come back！
回来
Ron！
罗恩
Salvia Hexia.
平安镇守
I open at the close.
我在结局开启
Hermione。Hermione.
赫敏 赫敏
You were right。Snitches have flesh memories.
你说的对 金色飞贼有肉体记忆
But I didn't catch the first snitch with my hand.
我第一次不是用手抓住的它
I almost swallowed it.
我差点把它吞了下去
- 「I open at the close。」 - Yeah，what do you think that means？
- 我在结局开启 - 是的 这什么意思
I don't know.
不知道
I found something as well.
我也有新发现
At first I thought it was an eye，but now I don't think it is.
我一直以为这是个眼睛的图片 但现在发现不是
It isn't a rune，and it isn't anywhere in Spellman's syllabary.
它不是魔文 也不在发音表里
Somebody inked it in.
是用墨水画的
It isn't part of the book，somebody drew it.
这不是书里的内容 是有人画的
Luna's dad was wearing it at Bill and Fleur's wedding.
比尔和芙蓉婚礼上 卢娜爸爸身上也戴了这标志
Why would someone draw it in a children's book？
谁会在儿童书上画这个
Hermione，I've been thinking.
赫敏 我一直在想
I want to go to Godric's Hollow.
我想去高锥克山谷
It's where I was born，It's where my parents died.
我在那出生 我父母也是在那死的
That's exactly where he'll expect you to go
那地方对你如此特别
because it means something to you.
他肯定料到你会去那
But it means something to him too，Hermione.
对他也一样重要 赫敏
You-Know-Who almost died there.
神秘人差点死在那儿
Isn't that exactly the type of place
把魂器藏在那
he'd be likely to hide a Horcrux？
不正合他意吗
I… it's dangerous，Harry.
我…太危险了 哈利
But even I have to admit
但不得不承认
recently I've been thinking we have to go there.
我最近也一直在想 得去那一趟
I think it's possible something else is hidden there.
还有样东西可能也藏在那儿
What？
什么
The Sword.
剑
If Dumbledore wanted you to find it，
如果邓不利多想让你找到
and didn't want it to falling in to the Ministry hands，
同时不希望落入魔法部之手
where better to hide it than
还有什么地方
the birthplace of the founder of Gryffindor.
会比格兰芬多的出生地更好呢
Hermione.
赫敏
Don't ever let me give you a haircut again.
以后别让我给你剪头发了
I still think that we should use the Polyjuice Potion.
咱们还是该喝复方汤剂的
No，this is where I was born.
不 这是我出生的地方
I'm not returning as someone else.
我不想扮成别人重返故乡
Harry，I think it's Christmas eve.
哈利 今天好像是平安夜
Listen.
听
Do you think they may be in there，Hermione？
你觉得他们在里面吗 赫敏
My Mom and Dad.
我的爸爸妈妈
Yeah，I think they would.
在吧
Ignotus Peverell.
伊格诺图斯·佩弗利尔
Hey，Harry？
哈利
（詹姆士·波特与莉莉·波特）
Merry Christmas，Hermione.
圣诞快乐 赫敏
Merry Christmas，Harry.
圣诞快乐 哈利
Harry，there is someone watching us.
哈利 有人正盯着我们
By the church.
教堂那边
I think I know who that is.
我大概知道是谁
- I don't like this，Harry。- Hermione，she knew Dumbledore.
- 我觉得不妥 哈利 - 赫敏 她认识邓不利多
She might have the sword.
剑可能在她那里
This is where they died，Hermione.
他们在这死的 赫敏
This is where he murdered them.
这是他杀死他们的地方
You're Bathilda，aren't you？
你是巴希达吗
Here，let me do that.
让我来吧
Miss Bagshot，who is this man？
巴沙特太太 这个男人是谁
Harry.
哈利
（《阿不思·邓不利多传》 丽塔·斯基特著）
Harry！
哈利
Are you feeling better？
感觉好点了吗
You've outdone yourself this time，Hermione.
这次移形成功了 赫敏
Forest of Dean.
这是迪恩森林
I came here once with Mum and Dad。Years ago.
几年前我和爸妈来过这
It's just how I remember it.
跟我记忆里的一模一样
The trees，the river，everything.
树林 小河 一切
Like nothings changed.
都如同没变一般
Not true of course，everything's changed.
但其实不是 一切都变了
If I brought my parents back here now，
就算我现在带父母回来
they probably wouldn't recognize any of it.
他们也未必能认出来了
Not the trees.
树林不在
Not the river.
小河不在
Not even me.
我也不再是那个我
Maybe we should just stay here，Harry.
也许我们就该待在这 哈利
Grow old.
慢慢老去
You wanted to know who was the boy in the photograph was.
你想知道照片里的男孩是谁吗
I know.
我知道
Gellert Grindelwald.
吉莱特·格林德沃
He's the thief I saw in Gregorovitch's wand shop.
我看到他在格里戈维奇的魔杖商店偷东西
Speaking of which，where is my wand？
对了 我的魔杖哪去了
Where's my wand，Hermione？
我的魔杖呢 赫敏
As we were leaving Godrics Hollow
离开高锥克山谷的时候
I cast a curse and it rebounded.
我施咒不小心击中了它
I'm sorry.
对不起
I tried to mend it，but wands are different.
我尽力了 但魔杖没那么容易修好
It's done.
算了
Leave me yours.
先用你的吧
Go inside and get warm.
你进去取暖
I'll take the locket as well.
挂坠也给我来戴
Lumos.
荧光闪烁
Accio sword！
宝剑飞来
Diffindo.
四分五裂
Hermione？
赫敏
Are you mental？
你疯了吗
It was you.
是你
Well yeah，bit obvious，I think.
是啊 很明显吧
And you cast the doe as well did you？
是你召唤出那雌鹿的吗
No，I thought that was you.
不是 我以为是你呢
No，my Patronus was a stag.
不 我的守护神是一只雄鹿
Right，now that was…
对 刚那头有…
Okay，Ron。Do it.
行了 罗恩 开始吧
I can't handle it.
我不能碰它
That thing affect me more than it effects you and Hermione.
我比你和赫敏更容易受它影响
- All the more reason。- No，I can't.
- 别说废话了 - 不 我不能
Then why are you here？
那你来干嘛
Why did you come back？
你回来干嘛
Now I'll have to speak to it in order for it to open.
现在我用蛇佬腔让它打开
When it does，don't hesitate.
一旦打开 别迟疑
I don't know what's in there，but it will put up a fight.
我不知道里面是什么 但肯定有一场恶战
The bit of Riddle that was in that diary tried to kill me.
日记中的神秘人想杀了我
One.
一
Two.
二
Three.
三
I have seen your heart and it is mine.
我曾见过你的心 它是属于我的
I have seen your dreams，Ronald Weasley.
我曾见过你的梦 罗恩·韦斯莱
And I see your fears.
我也曾见过你的恐惧
Least loved by your mother，who craved a daughter.
母亲的爱予你最少 她更希望是个女孩
Least loved by the girl，who prefers your friend.
心上人之爱予你最少 她更爱你的朋友
Ron，kill it！
罗恩 快刺
We were better without you.
没有你我们会更好
Happy without you.
更开心
Who would look at you？Who has，Harry Potter.
有了哈利·波特 谁会看你一眼
What are you，compared to the chosen one？
和被选中的人相比 你算什么
Ron，it's lying！
罗恩 它在说谎
Your mother confessed，she would prefer me as a son.
你妈跟我说过 更希望我做她的儿子
What woman would take you？
哪个女人会喜欢你
You are nothing… nothing.
你和他相比一无是处
Nothing compared to him.
一无是处
Just think.
想想
There are only three to go.
只剩下三个了
Hermione？
赫敏
Is everything alright？
还好吗
It's fine。Actually，yeah，it's more than fine.
很好 应该是好极了
Hey.
嘿
You…
你
…A complete ass，Ronald Weasley！
罗恩·韦斯莱 十足的大混蛋
You show up here after weeks and you say 'hey'？
走了几个星期 回来就说声 嘿
Where's my wand，Harry？
我的魔杖呢 哈利
- Where's my wand？- I don't know.
- 我的魔杖呢 - 我不知道
Harry Potter。You give me my wand！
哈利·波特 把魔杖给我
- How come he's got your wand？- Never mind why's he got my wand.
- 他怎么拿你的魔杖 - 关你什么事
What is that？
这是什么
You destroyed it.
你摧毁了魂器
And how is it that you just
你怎么会拿到
happen to have the sword of Gryffindor？
格兰芬多剑的呢
It's a long story.
说来话长
Don't think this changes anything.
别以为这样我就会饶了你
Of course not。I only just destroyed a bloody Horcrux，
当然不会 我只是摧毁了一个魂器
why will that change anything.
你当然不会原谅我
Look，I wanted to come back as soon as I left.
我刚走就后悔了
I just didn't know how to find you.
只是不知道上哪找你们
Yeah，how did you find us？
那你怎么找到的
With this。Doesn't just turn off lights.
这个 不只能熄灯
I don't know how it works，
我不知道它是怎么做到的
but Christmas morning I sleeping in this little pub.
但圣诞节早上 我睡在一个小酒馆
Keeping away from some snatchers.
躲避那些掠夺贼
- When I heard it。- It？
- 我听到它 - 它
A voice.
一个声音
Your voice，Hermione.
你的声音 赫敏
Comin' out of it.
从这里面发出来
And what exactly did I say if I may ask？
那我都说了些什么
My name.
我的名字
Just my name.
只有我的名字
Like a whisper.
像是轻声低语
So I took it，clicked it…
所以我拿出来 打开
and this tiny ball of light appeared.
出现了一个小小的蓝色光球
And I knew，sure enough.
我就知道了 非常肯定
It floated towards me，the ball of light.
那个小光球向我飘来
Went right to my chest，straight through me。Right here.
落入了我的胸膛 就从这里
I knew it was gonna take me where I needed to go，
我知道它会把我带到想去的地方
so I disapparated.
我用了幻影移形
I came to this hillside.
就到了山的这边
It was dark，I had no idea where I was.
当时很黑 我不知道身处何地
I just hoped that one of you would show yourself.
我只希望你们当中有谁能出现
You did.
你出现了
I've always liked these flames Hermione makes.
我一直很喜欢赫敏造的小火苗
How long do you reckon she'll stay mad at me？
你觉得她还要生我的气多久
Just keep talking about that little ball of light touching your heart.
多说几遍那个小光球融入你心的故事
- And she'll come around。- It's true。Every word.
- 她的气就消了 - 千真万确
This is gonna sound crazy.
可能听起来不可思议
But I think，thats why Dumbledore left it to me.
但我想这就是邓不利多把它给我的原因
The Deluminator.
这个熄灯器
I think he knew that somehow I'd need to find my way back.
他知道我可能需要找到回来的路
That she'd lead me.
她将为我指明道路
You know，I just realized。You need a wand，don't you？
我刚想到 你需要根魔杖是吗
- Yeah。- I got one here.
- 是啊 - 我这有一根
It's a Blackthorn，10 inches，nothing special.
黑刺李木的 十英寸 没什么特别之处
I reckon it'll do.
应该还能用
Took it off a snatcher a couple of weeks ago.
几星期前从一个掠夺贼那抢的
Don't tell Hermione this.
别让赫敏知道
They're a bit dim，snatchers.
掠夺贼有点傻
This one is definitely partial to smelling.
但嗅觉非常灵敏
- Engorgio。- Put it out.
- 速速变大 - 快弄灭
What's going on in there？
里面出什么事了
- Nothing！- Nothing！
- 没事 - 没事
We need to talk.
我们得谈谈
Yeah，alright.
好啊
I want to go see Xenophilius Lovegood.
我想去找谢诺菲留斯·洛夫古德
Sorry？
什么
See this？It's a letter Dumbledore wrote to Grindelwald.
看这个 这是邓不利多写给格林德瓦的信
Look at the signature.
看这个签名
It's the mark again.
又是这个符号
It keeps cropping up.
它时时闪现
In Beedle the Bard，in the graveyard in Godric's Hollow.
在诗翁彼豆故事集里 在高锥克山谷的墓地
It was there too.
在那也有
- Where？- Outside Gregorvitch's wand shop.
- 哪 - 格里戈维奇的魔杖店外
- What does it mean？- Look.
- 它代表什么意思 - 听着
You've got no idea where the next Horcrux is，and neither do I.
你我都不知道下个魂器在哪
But this，this means something.
但这个 这个一定代表着什么
I'm sure of it.
我十分确定
Yeah。Hermione's right.
是啊 赫敏说的对极了
We ought to see Lovegood.
我们应该去见见洛夫古德
Let's vote on it.
还是投票表决吧
Those in favor.
同意的举手
You're not still mad at him，are you？
你不会还在生他的气吧
I'm always mad at him.
他什么时候让我省过心
Luna，we're here.
卢娜 我们来了
Keep off the Dirigible Plums.
别碰飞艇李
（《唱唱反调》主编 谢·洛夫古德）
Keep off the Dirigible Plums.
别碰飞艇李
What is it？Who are you？
怎么了 你们是谁
What do you want？
想要干什么
Hello，Mr。Lovegood.
您好 洛夫古德先生
I'm Harry Potter，we met a few months ago.
我是哈利·波特 我们几个月前见过
Can we come in？
我们能进来吗
- Where is Luna？- Luna？
- 卢娜去哪了 - 卢娜吗
She'll be along.
她一会儿就来
So，how can I help you，Mr。Potter？
我能帮您先什么呢 波特先生
Well，actually，
实际上
it was about something you were wearing around your neck at the wedding.
是关于你在婚礼上戴在脖子上的
It was a symbol.
那个标志
- You mean this？- Yes.
- 你是说这个吗 - 是的
That's it exactly.
正是这个
What we wondered is… what is it？
我们想知道 这是什么
What is it？
这是什么吗
Well，it's the sign of the Deathly Hallows，of course.
这还用说 死亡圣器的标志啊
- The What？- The What？
- 什么 - 什么
The Deathly Hallows.
死亡圣器
I assume you are all familiar with the tale of the three brothers.
我想你们都熟悉三兄弟的传说吧
- Yes… - Yes.
- 是的 - 是的
No.
不
I have it in here.
我这里面有
There were once three brothers，
从前有三兄弟
who were traveling along a lonely winding road…
在一条僻静的羊肠小道上赶路
- At twilight。- Midnight.
- 天色已近黄昏 - 是午夜
Mom always said midnight.
妈妈一直说是午夜
Twilight's fine，better actually.
黄昏也不错 实际上更好
- Do you want to read it？- Uh，no.
- 你想来念吗 - 你念就好了
There were once three brothers，who were traveling along…
从前有三兄弟
a lonely winding road…
在一条僻静的羊肠小道上赶路
At twilight.
天色已近黄昏
In time the brothers reached
不久 三兄弟来到一条河边
a river too treacherous to pass.
河水太险 无法渡过
But they were learned in the magical arts，
但三兄弟精通魔法
the three brothers simply waved their wands，and made a bridge.
他们只挥了下魔杖 就变出了一座桥
Before they could cross however，
然而他们正准备过桥时
they found their path blocked by a hooded figure.
却发现一个戴兜帽的身影挡住了去路
It was Death.
那就是死神
And he felt cheated.
他觉得被欺骗了
Cheated，
因为
because travelers would always drown in the river.
旅行者通常会淹死于此
But Death was cunning.
但死神很狡猾
He pretended to congratulate the three brothers on their magic.
他假装称赞三兄弟的魔法
And said，that each had earned a prize for having
还说 他们凭着聪明才智躲过了死神
been clever enough to evade him.
每人可以获得一个奖励
The oldest asked for a wand，more powerful than any in existence.
老大想要一根天底下最强大的魔杖
So death fashioned him a
因此死神就用旁边的一棵接骨木树
wand from an elder tree that stood nearby.
给他做了根魔杖
The second brother decided he wanted to humiliate death even further，
老二决定继续羞辱死神
and asked for the power to recall loved ones from the grave.
他想拥有能让死去的爱人复活的能力
So Death plucked a stone from the river and offered it to him.
因此死神就从河里变了块石头给他
Finally，Death turned to the third brother.
最后 死神转向老三
A humble man，
老三很谦逊
he asked for something that would allow him to go forth from that place，
他要一件能让他离开那里
without being followed by death.
而不会被死神跟随的东西
And so it was that death reluctantly handed over his own cloak of invisibility.
死神极不情愿地 把自己的隐形斗篷给了他
The first brother traveled to a distant village.
老大来到了一个遥远的山村
While with the elder wand in hand，
用那根接骨木做成的老魔杖
he killed a wizard with whom he had once quarrels.
杀死了一个与他不合的巫师
Drunk with the power that the
老魔杖赋予他的魔力令他欣喜若狂
elder wand had given him.
喝得酩酊大醉
He bragged of his invincibility.
他四处炫耀自己的无敌威力
But that night…
但就在那晚
Another wizard stole the wand
另一个巫师偷走了魔杖
and slit the brother's throat for good measure.
并割断了他的喉咙
And so death took the first brother for his own.
就这样死神取走了老大的性命
The second brother journeyed to his home.
老二旅行回家
Where he took the stone and turned it twice in hand.
他拿出复活石并且在手里转了两次
To his delight
令他欣喜的是
the girl he'd once hoped to marry before her untimely death，
他曾想迎娶却不幸早逝的女孩
appeared before him.
出现在了他身前
Yet soon she turned sad and cold
但不久她就变得悲伤难耐 心灰意冷
for she did not belong in the mortal world.
因为她并不属于人间
Driven mad with hopeless longing，
渴求无望 老二陷入了疯癫
the second brother killed himself so as to join her.
为了能和她真正在一起 他自杀身亡
And so death took the second brother.
就这样 死神取走了老二的性命
As for the third brother，Death searched for many years
而说到老三 死神找了他好多年
but was never able to find him.
却始终没能找到他
Only when he had attained a great age did the youngest brother，
兄弟中最小的老三 一直活到了很大年纪
shed the cloak of invisibility and give it to his son.
才脱下隐形斗篷 交给了他儿子
He then greeted death as a old friend
然后他像老朋友见面一样迎接了死神
and went with him gladly departing this life as equals.
并以平等的身份与死神一起 安然离开了人间
So there you are。Those are the Deathly Hallows.
就是这样 这些就是死亡圣器
I'm sorry sir，I still don't quite understand.
抱歉 先生 我还是不太理解
The Elder wand.
老魔杖
The most powerful wand ever made.
世上最具威力的魔杖
The resurrection stone.
复活石
The cloak of invisibility.
隐形斗篷
Together，they make the Deathly Hallows.
合在一起 就组成了死亡圣器
Together，they make one master of death.
合在一起 便能主宰生死
That mark was on the grave in Godrics Hollow.
在戈德里克山谷的坟墓上也有那个标记
Um，Mr。Lovegood，
洛夫古德先生
does the Peverell family
佩弗利尔家族和
have anything to do with the Deathly Hallows？
死亡圣器有什么关系吗
Ignotus，excuse me。And his brothers Cadmus and Antioch，
伊格诺图斯 借过 还有他的兄弟卡德摩斯和安提俄克
thought to be the original owners of the Hallows，
被认为是圣器最初的拥有者
and therefore the inspiration for the story.
因此也是这个故事的灵感来源
But your tea has gone cold.
你们的茶都凉了
I'll be right back.
我马上回来
Let's get out of here.
咱们快撤吧
I don't want to drink anymore of that stuff.
我再也不想喝那玩意了
Hot or cold.
管他是热的还是凉的
- Thank you，Sir。- You forgot the water.
- 谢谢您 先生 - 您忘记烧水了
- Water？- For the tea.
- 什么水 - 泡茶的水
How silly of me.
我真是太傻了
It's really nice sir，but we really should be going any way.
谢谢您的好意 但我们也该走了
No，you do not！
不 你们不能走
Sir？
先生
You're my only hope.
你是我唯一的希望
They were angry，you see，from what I've been writing.
我写的东西让他们很恼火
So they took her.
所以他们抓走了她
They took my children.
他们抓走了我的孩子
My children.
我的孩子
Oh，it's really you，then it'll work.
要真是你 就有救了
Who took her，sir？
谁把她抓走了 先生
Voldemort.
伏地魔
I got him！
我抓到他了
Treacherous little bleeder！
背信弃义的混球
Is there no one we can trust？
难道就没人可信了吗
They kidnapped her because he supported me.
卢娜是因为他支持我才被食死徒抓走的
He was just desperate.
他只是被逼无奈
I'll do the enchantments.
我去施防护魔法
Hello，beautiful.
你好啊 美女
Well，don't hang about。Snatch 'em.
别傻站着啊 抓住他们
Harry。Tell me what to do.
哈利 告诉我怎么做
Tell me，where it is.
告诉我它在哪里
Grindelwald。Grindelwald.
格林德瓦 格林德瓦
I knew you'd come，one day.
我知道总有一天你会来的
But surely you must know.
但你一定知道
I no longer have what you seek.
你要找的东西已不在我手里了
Tell me，Grindelwald，tell me where it is.
告诉我 格林德瓦 告诉我它在哪里
Tell me who possesses it.
告诉我谁拿了它
The elder wand lies with him，of course.
老魔杖当然和他在一起
Buried in the earth.
深埋地底
Dumbledore.
与邓布利多一起
The Hallows exist.
圣器真的存在
But he's only after one of them，the last one.
但他只在找最后一个
He knows where it is.
他知道它在哪里
He's gonna have it by the end of the night.
天亮之前他就会得到它
You know who's had the elder wand？
你知道老魔杖在谁那吗
- Don't touch her！- Leave him.
- 不要碰她 - 放开他
Your boyfriend will get much worse
如果你男朋友再不老实点的话
than that if he doesn't learn to behave himself.
可会吃更多苦头哦
What happened to you，ugly？
你的脸怎么了 丑八怪
No，not you.
不是说你
- What's your name？- Dudley。Vernon Dudley.
- 你叫什么 - 达力 弗农·达力
Check it.
查下名单
And you，my lovely.
你呢 我的小甜心
What do they call you？
他们叫你什么啊
Penelope Clearwater，half-blood.
珀涅罗珀·克里尔沃特 混血
There's no Vernon Dudley on here.
这上面没有弗农·达力
You hear that ugly？This says you're lying.
听到没 丑八怪 你在撒谎
How come you don't want us to know who you are？
为什么不想让我们知道你是谁呢
It's wrong，I told you who I am.
你弄错了 我已经说过我的名字了
Change of plan.
计划有变
We're not taking this lot to the Ministry.
不能把这些大鱼交给魔法部
Get，Draco.
把德拉科叫来
Well？
怎样
I can't be sure.
我不能确定
Look closely，son.
近点看 儿子
If we are the ones to hand Potter over to the Dark Lord.
如果我们能把波特交给黑魔王
Everything would be forgiven，
之前的一切都会一笔勾消
it would be as it was，understand？
我们还会像以前一样受宠 明白吗
Now we won't be forgetting who really actually caught him.
希望你不要忘了是谁抓到他的
I hope，Mr。Malfoy.
马尔福先生
- You dare to talk to me like that in my own house！- Lucius！
- 你竟敢在我家这样跟我说话 - 卢修斯
Do not be shy，sweetie。Come closer.
别害羞 宝贝 走近点看
Now，if this isn't who you think it is，Draco，
德拉科 要是我们把黑魔王叫来
and we call Him。He'll kill us all.
而他又不是波特 那我们就都完蛋
We need to be absolutely sure.
得确保万无一失
- What's wrong with his face？- Yes，what is wrong with his face？
- 他的脸怎么回事 - 是啊 他的脸怎么回事
He came to us like that.
我们抓到他时 他就这样
Something he picked up in the forest，I reckon.
我想是在树林里中了什么咒吧
An interesting jinx。Was it you，dear？
真不凑巧啊 是你干的吗 宝贝
Give me her wand，
把你的魔杖给我
let's see what your last spell was.
让我瞧瞧你最后施的什么咒语
Got you.
抓住你了
What's that？
那是什么
Where'd you get that from？
你在哪找到的
It was in her bag when we searched her.
从她包里搜出来的
I reckon it's mine now.
现在是我的了
Are you mad？
你疯了吗
Get out！Get out！
滚出去 滚
Cissy，put the boys in the cellar.
西茜 把这两个男孩关进地窖
I want a conversation with this one.
我要和她好好谈谈
Girl to girl！
姑娘间的谈话
What are we gonna do？
我们该怎么办
We can't leave Hermione alone with her.
不能让赫敏和她单独在一起
Ron？
罗恩
Harry？
哈利
Luna？
卢娜
That Sword is meant to be in my vault now，
那剑本该躺在我的金库里
how did you get it？
你是怎么得到的
Did you and your friend's take it from my vault？
你和你的朋友从我的金库里偷来的吗
I didn't take anything！
我什么都没拿
I don't believe you.
我才不信
- We have to do something！- There is no way out of here.
- 我们得做点什么 - 这里根本没有出路
We tried everything。It's enchanted.
我们试过各种方法 这里被施了魔法
You're bleeding，Harry.
你在流血 哈利
That's a curious thing to keep on yourself.
这种保持清醒的方法真稀奇啊
Help us！
救救我们
- Let her go。- You go，get back！
- 放开她 - 你滚开 退后
You，Goblin。Come with me.
小妖精 你跟我来
Dobby？What are you doing here？
多比 你怎么到这来了
Dobby's come to rescue，Harry Potter of course.
多比当然是来救你 哈利·波特
Dobby will always be there for Harry Potter.
多比会永远保护哈利·波特
Are you saying that you can apparate in and out of this room？
你是说你可以移形出入这个地牢吗
Could you take us with you？
你能带我们一起吗
Of course，sir，I'm a elf.
当然 先生 我是个精灵
Works for me.
我同意
Right，Dobby，I want you to take Luna and Mr。Ollivander…
很好 多比 我想让你带着卢娜和奥利凡德先生去…
Shell Cottage，on the outskirts of Tinworth.
贝壳小宅 在汀沃斯的近郊
Trust me.
相信我
When ever you're ready，sir.
整装待发了 先生
Sir？I like her very much！
你叫我先生吗 我真喜欢她
Meet me at top of the stairs in ten seconds.
十秒后在楼梯口见面
Who gets his wand？
谁要他的魔杖
I'm going to ask you once more，goblin.
我最后再问你一遍 小妖精
Think very，very carefully.
你要好好想清楚了
- How did they get there？- I don't know.
- 他们是怎么进去的 - 我不知道
You don't know？Why were you doing your job？
不知道 你吃白饭的啊
Who got into my vault？
谁闯入了我的金库
Who stole it？
谁偷了它
Who… Stole it？
谁 偷了它
It's impossible to break into Gringotts，the sword is there.
没人能闯入古灵阁 宝剑还在那里
（泥巴种）
Then how is it that it's out then？
那它怎么在这里
There is no place safer，than Gringotts.
没有比古灵阁更安全的地方了
Liar！
骗子
Consider yourself lucky，goblin.
算你走运 小妖精
- The same won't be said for this one。- Like hell！
- 这一个可没这么幸运了 - 去死吧
Expelliarmus.
除你武器
Stupefy！
昏昏倒地
Stop！
住手
Drop your wands.
放下魔杖
I said，drop them！
听到没 放下魔杖
Pick 'em up，Draco，now！Well，well，well.
德拉科 快去捡起来 好 很好
Look what we have here.
看看这是谁啊
It's Harry Potter.
是哈利·波特
He's all bright，shiny and new again.
他又焕然一新 神气十足了
Just in time for the Dark Lord.
是时候叫黑魔王来了
Call him.
召唤他
召唤吧
Stupefy！
昏昏倒地
Stupid elf！You could have kill me！
蠢精灵 你差点杀了我
Dobby never meant to kill.
多比从不想杀任何人
Dobby only meant to maim or seriously injure.
多比只想把你弄残或是重伤
How dare you take a witch's wand.
你怎敢夺走巫师的魔杖
How dare you defy your masters.
你怎敢反抗你的主人
Dobby has no master.
多比没有主人
Dobby is a free elf.
多比是一个自由的精灵
And Dobby has come to save Harry Potter and his friends.
多比是来救哈利·波特和他的朋友的
Hermione，are you all right？
赫敏 你们都还好吗
We're safe。We're all safe.
我们安全了 安全了
Harry Potter…
哈利·波特
Dobby！
多比
Dobby，you're all right then，hold on.
多比 你会好起来的 坚持住
Hold on，okay？
坚持住 好吗
Just hold on，okay？We're going to fix it.
再坚持一下 我们会治好你的
Hermione，you have something…
赫敏 你包里…
In your bag。Hermione！
一定有东西可以救他 赫敏
Come on.
说啊
Help me.
帮帮我
Such a beautiful place，
这地方真美
to be with friends.
还能和朋友们在一起
Dobby is happy，
多比很开心
to be with be with his friend，
能和朋友在一起
Harry Potter.
哈利·波特
We should close his eyes.
把他的眼睛阖上吧
Don't you think？
你觉得呢
There，now he could be sleeping.
好了 现在他可以安眠了
I want to bury him.
我想安葬他
Properly，without magic.
要让他去得体面 我要亲手安葬